dorlingkindersley-uk.co.uk 2010-06-22

# Dorling Kindersley: Copyright - Privacy Policies

Changes to Privacy Policy  
The Privacy Policy was updated on 15/12/2008

* * *

  * Privacy Policy - Adult
  * Privacy Policy \- Children
  * Privacy Policy \- Parents & Teachers

PRIVACY POLICY - ADULT  
This website ("the Site") is owned and operated by Dorling Kindersley Limited.

How to contact us  
If you have any questions about the Site or our privacy policy, please contact us by any of the following methods:

The Editor, dk.com  
DK Online Department  
Dorling Kindersley Limited  
80 Strand  
London  
WC2R 0RL  
United Kingdom

Email: [editor@dk.com](mailto:editor@dk.com)

Our approach to your privacy  
We want people who visit the Site to be able to take part fully in the activities and offers we provide. We also want to make sure that when we collect information from you we do so in a way that does not infringe your right to privacy. This Privacy Policy is designed to give you useful information about your rights and the way we collect and use personal information.

We do not ask you to disclose any more information than is reasonably necessary to enable you to participate in an activity on the Site and to ensure that the Site is in keeping with our customers' needs.

We do not generally disclose personal information we have collected from you through the Site to third parties. We may do so sometimes, in which case we will say so when the information is collected and you will be able to inform us that you do not want us to do this. This will not stop you enjoying the Site, you can simply tell us that you are happy for us to have the information so you can take part in the activities we offer, but that you do not want us to pass that information on.

Besides what we describe in this Privacy Policy, we do not maintain any personal information obtained from users through the Site in a retrievable form. 

The information we collect and how we use it  

  * When you subscribe to receive any of our email newsletters we ask for your email address so that we can send you the material that you want.
  * On all informative emails and newsletters that we send, we give you the option to unsubscribe.
  * When you enter competitions, we usually ask you for your name, email and residential address. This is so that we can let you know if you have won anything, send you your prize and let other people (such as other users of the Site, the public and our own employees) know about our competitions and their winners.
  * When you send e-postcards, we will ask you for your name and email address so we can let whoever receives the postcard know who sent it.
  * When you submit reviews for display on the Site, we ask for your name (as you would like us to publish it) and your email address (which we will not publish) so we can contact you in relation to your review. If you plan to submit a review to the Site, please take note of your obligations under the Terms and Conditions of the Site.
  * When you purchase products online, we will need to pass on your name, address and payment details to the third parties who help us to fulfill your order. For further details about information security on the Site, please see our Safe Shopping Policy.

We only keep the personal information you submit for these purposes until we have made use of it in these ways.

Cookies  
We use cookies on the Site. Cookies are small files that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. They enable us to recognize your web browser. In effect, cookies tell us when you have visited the Site and where you have been, but they do not identify you personally. We use cookies to see how often people visit the Site and what they look at. This helps us to know what parts of the Site are popular - what people are interested in - so we can make sure we have more interesting material on the Site in future. We also use cookies to make it easier for you to get around the Site. For example, when you first visit us we ask you to click on a flag that directs you to the Site for the country you are in. When you come back, we use cookies to remind us where you want to go and we take you there directly. If you don't want us to be able to do this, your browser's help section should be able to tell you how you can disable or filter cookies and how to arrange for your browser to tell you when you've been sent a new cookie. If you choose to disable or filter the cookies we use, it may mean that the Site's functions do not work as intended.

Aggregate Information  
We track the following information on the Site anonymously, or as 'aggregate' data: users' ISP's, the domain names of the pages from which users come to the Site, users' browsers and operating systems.

back to top

* * *

PRIVACY POLICY - CHILDREN  
**Hey you! Yeah, you! Are you 13 yet? You're not?**   
Well, then it's your lucky day. You don't need to read all this stuff, just ask one of the grown ups you live with, or your teacher, to do all the work. Ask them to click on this link and start reading for you. If you're 13 already, we're afraid you've got some reading to do.

So, who are we?  
This is Dorling Kindersley Limited's Site.

Where are we?  
If you want to ask us a question about the Site or what we do with things you tell us about yourself:

Write to us at:

The Editor, dk.com  
DK Online Department  
Dorling Kindersley Limited  
80 Strand London  
WC2R 0RL  
United Kingdom

Or send us an email: [editor@dk.com](mailto:editor@dk.com)

Who are you?   
You know the answer to this one already, but we don't. So sometimes we will ask you to tell us, along with where you live, how we can get in touch with you (your email, your address) and what you like and don't like - your hobbies, your favourite authors, stuff like that. 

When are we going to bug you?  
You've probably already seen on some pages of the Site that we ask you questions about yourself, we do that when:

  * You sign up to receive any of our email newsletters. When you do, we’ll usually ask for your email address so that we can email the newsletters to you. We’ll let you know in our email how you can unsubscribe if you don’t want to receive anymore newsletters.
  * You go in for a competition. When you do, we'll usually ask for your name and address so we can let you know if you win and we can send you a prize! We might also want to tell other people that you won and maybe put up your entry on the Site. We'll ask you to tell us if we can before we do.
  * You send an e-postcard. If you do, we'll need your name and email address so we can make sure you get a copy of the e-postcard you sent.
  * You send us a review, poem, joke or story. If you do this and we decide to post it on the Site, we'll need to know who and where you are so we can tell you: "We want your review on the site!"
  * When you submit a review for the Site. Then we ask for your name (that you want us to publish) and your email address (which we won't publish) so we can contact you about your review.
  * If you plan to send in a review or post comments on the Site, ask a parent or other adult to check out Terms and Conditions and to help you with what you send.
  * You buy stuff, then we'll need to use your name, address and payment details to make sure we send you what you've bought. We may need to tell these to other people who help us to get your order to you too. Remember, you should get a parent or another adult to help you if you want to shop online.

You tell us about yourself - then what?  
If you come and visit the Site then we promise that we won't go telling anyone else the stuff you've told us. That would be pretty rude. The only time we'll share what you've said to us about yourself will be when we've already told you we were going to and you'll be able to tell us "no".

Hey you! You're not 13 yet are you?  
Didn't we tell you not to read all this? Aren't you bored yet? Ask an adult to read what's at the other end of this link.

back to top

* * *

PRIVACY POLICY - PARENTS & TEACHERS  
This is the web site of Dorling Kindersley Limited.

How to contact us  
If you have any questions about the Site or our Privacy Policy, please contact us by:

Writing to:

The Editor, dk.com  
DK Online Department  
Dorling Kindersley Limited  
80 Strand  
London WC2R 0RL  
United Kingdom

Or send an email: [editor@dk.com](mailto:editor@dk.com)

Our approach to children's privacy  
We want children who visit the Site to be able to take part fully in the activities and offers we provide. We also want to make sure that when we collect information from children we do so in a way that does not infringe their right to privacy. This Privacy Policy is designed to give you useful information about your child's rights and the way we collect and use personal information. We do not ask children to disclose any more information than is reasonably necessary to enable them to participate in an activity on the Site.

We do not disclose personal information we have collected from children through this Site to third parties.

Besides what we describe in this Privacy Policy, we do not maintain any personal information obtained from children through the Site in a retrievable form. 

The information we collect and how we use it  
Please help your children when they use the Site to ensure that they get the most out of the experience. While we make every effort to ensure that they can visit and use the Site safely and easily, nothing can substitute for parental/adult supervision and guidance.

When children want to participate in activities on the Site, this is the sort of information we ask for and how we use it: 

  * When children subscribe to receive any of our email newsletters we ask them for their email address so that we can send them the material that they have asked for.
  * On all informative emails and newsletters that we send, we give an option to unsubscribe.
  * When children enter competitions, we usually ask for their names and email and residential addresses. This is so that we can let them know if they have won anything, send them their prizes and also let other people (such as other users of the Site, the public and our own employees) know about our competitions and their winners.
  * When children send e-postcards, we will ask them for their names and email addresses. This is so we can let whoever receives the postcard know who sent it.
  * When children send in reviews of our books, we will ask them for their names and email addresses. This is so that we can post their reviews on the Site, and give them credit for what they have written. We do not publish email addresses of children.
  * If children submit reviews for display on the Site, we ask for their names (as they would like us to publish them) and email addresses (which we will not publish) so we can contact them in relation to their reviews. If your child plans to submit a review to the Site, please take note of their obligations under the Terms and Conditions of the Site and help them to comply with them.
  * When you purchase products online with your children, we need to pass on the name, address and payment details that you give to third parties who help us to fulfill our orders. For further details about information security on the Site, please see our Safe Shopping Policy

We only keep the personal information children submit for these purposes until we have made use of it in these ways.

Cookies  
We use cookies on the Site. Cookies are small files that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your web browser. They enable us to recognize your web browser. In effect, cookies tell us when you have visited the Site and where you have been, but they do not identify you personally. We use cookies to see how often people visit the Site and what they look at. This helps us to know what parts of the Site are popular - what people are interested in - so we can make sure we have more interesting material on the Site in future. We also use cookies to make it easier for you to get around the Site. For example, when you first visit us we ask you to click on a flag that directs you to the Site for the country you are in. When you come back, we use cookies to remind us where you want to go and we take you there directly. If you don't want us to be able to do this, your browser's help section should be able to tell you how you can disable or filter cookies and how to arrange for your browser to tell you when you've been sent a new cookie. If you choose to disable or filter the cookies we use, it may mean that the Site's functions do not work as intended.

Aggregate Information  
We track the following information on the Site anonymously, or as 'aggregate' data: users' ISP's, the domain names of the pages from which users come to the Site, users' browsers and operating systems.

Children under 13 years of age  
We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate in the activities offered on the Site. If your child is younger than 13, we ask you to play an active role in safeguarding his or her privacy when using the Site.

When your child takes part in an offer or activity on the Site where we ask him or her for personal information, we may ask for your consent or for you to indicate if you do not consent (depending on the type of activity/information being gathered).

If you have children who are under 13, we ask you to complete their entry forms for competitions run on the Site. We will notify you if your child wins a competition and send any prize to you. We will also obtain your prior consent before publishing the name, age and photograph of your child if he or she wins a competition. 

Older children  
If your child is older than 13, we will ask him or her to give consent personally if we plan to keep or use his or her information for anything (we will also say what we plan to do with it). Please help your children with this. 

back to top
